<row Id="4308" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="16539" CreationDate="2011-12-21T23:30:00.720" Score="57" ViewCount="14125" Body="&lt;p&gt;Some people have the amazing ability to doze off whenever and wherever they are. For the rest of us, sleeping on planes is a constant battle of trying to get comfortable in a cramped space. There are lots of options: special pillows, leaning against the window, folding over flaps on the headrest, leaning on the shoulder of a friend next to you, etc. Certainly something must work...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What have you found to be the best way to comfortably sleep on a plane (in a standard economy seat; first class is a whole different world)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="396" LastEditorUserId="101" LastEditDate="2011-12-28T21:40:26.517" LastActivityDate="2013-11-03T00:25:16.783" Title="What is the most comfortable way to sleep on a plane?" Tags="&lt;air-travel&gt;&lt;aircraft&gt;&lt;sleeping&gt;" AnswerCount="10" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="23" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<-- Answers to original question -->

<row Id="4309" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2011-12-22T00:44:40.477" Score="18" Body="&lt;p&gt;Personally I've given up, and in some ways, since I did that, I've actually ended up sleeping more - quite the paradox!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don't go onboard PLANNING to sleep.  My view is that I'll be settling in for 20-something hours of movies (CHC to LON).  I can stay awake pretty well, but find it very difficult to get to sleep sitting up.  Anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I've found as a result is that I no longer get stressed &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; and failing to get to sleep.  And I'm more relaxed.  Then if after 5 or 6 movies during the 'night' period, I start to feel sleepy, I'll relax for a few minutes between movies with my eyes closed.  Sometimes I fall asleep, other times it's just a chance to rest my eyes between action flicks ;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also start choosing tv episodes during this period, rather than movies, as it affords me more chances to try to sleep, and I don't miss as much if I do!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now of course, this is all economy class.  I also try for the aisle seat, as nothing is more annoying than trying to sleep and having my neighbour's arms bumping me.  I know the window seat means less interruptions and probably a wall to lean against (sometimes it's too far away), but I feel trapped in the window seat as I hate waking my neighbours to get up and walk around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If at all possible, get the emergency exit row, window seat, as that gives you a wall and space to get up and stretch out as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After that, it's pillows (if you have) blankets and whatever else makes you feel more comfortable.  I've even curled across two seats in the past, although it's very, very tight, and tend to get passengers hitting my feet as they walk past in the aisle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="101" LastActivityDate="2011-12-22T00:44:40.477" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="4312" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2011-12-22T04:30:37.250" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've known some friends of mine to take a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dimenhydrinate&quot;&gt;Gravol&lt;/a&gt; (motion sickness &amp;amp; relaxant pill also known as Dramamine or Dimenhydrinate) and they can fall asleep quite easily on the plane.  This doesn't work for me but I've known it to work for others and felt it was worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastEditorUserId="396" LastEditDate="2011-12-23T05:58:34.117" LastActivityDate="2011-12-23T05:58:34.117" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="4339" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2011-12-22T19:06:40.090" Score="28" Body="&lt;p&gt;The problem of airplanes is the sheer number of ways in which it differs from your normal sleeping routine:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noise (silence is pretty much impossible)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light (they're never totally off even in &quot;sleep mode&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Comfort (unless you sleep on a rock-hard mattress, not the same)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Temperature (the cabin tends to be cold on long flights)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peace (interruption from other passengers trying to get by, e.g. to go to the bathroom)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Position (not a bed, obviously)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With all of these conditions differing from your normal night's sleep, your body has a very tough time relaxing into that sweet circadian rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the remedy is to tackle as many of these as you can and make them as similar as possible to your normal sleeping conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noise:&lt;/strong&gt; Get ear plugs. Good ones. Not the flimsy foam jobbies. I use musician's ear plugs by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vater.com/products/product.cfm?M=287&quot;&gt;Vater&lt;/a&gt;, which have switchable red and green filters. The green are 19db and great for live music. The red are 21db and great for getting near-silence (or seeing the legendary loud performances of the band My Bloody Valentine). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.etymotic.com/hp/&quot;&gt;Etymotic&lt;/a&gt; are also a good source of quality musician-style earplugs, but they don't have the nifty switchable filter system.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light:&lt;/strong&gt; Get a comfortable sleeping mask. Try it on in the store to make sure it's opaque and fully obscures the light from your eyes...I've been surprised more than once by a mask that looked opaque and turned out not to be. Also, some airlines will provide masks, so ask if you forget yours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comfort:&lt;/strong&gt; Some like those neck pillows, but I'm partial to one of those compressible little memory foam travel pillows with a pillowcase.  Stuffs down small, and while no substitute for a comfy mattress it does at least give your &lt;em&gt;head&lt;/em&gt; the sensation of comfort. Much better than the lumpy standard issue plane pillows.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; Always snag a blanket on the way into the plane, and &lt;em&gt;wear layers&lt;/em&gt;. Silk or wool underwear is a good idea so if you perspire in your sleep you won't lose warmth as a result.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace:&lt;/strong&gt; Always get the window seat. I understand the sentiment of those who don't like having to get past other passengers to get to the bathroom, but my mindset is &quot;It's either them or me, so it's going to be them.&quot; With a window seat, you'll be far more likely to be undisturbed than someone in the middle or aisle seats.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position:&lt;/strong&gt; Not much you can do here, unless you fly one of those airlines like British Airways that has put some extra effort into making their seats more bed-like even in the economy class.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, on most airlines, you can achieve 5 out of 6 with a reasonable degree of quality, leaving Position as the only variable you haven't corrected for. After many, many flights in my lifetime, I've found that conquering all 5 of the others is the key to getting a decent rest on the plane, complete with dreams worth writing in my journal about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try it, and you might be surprised how much sleep you can get on a crowded plane.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1476" LastEditorDisplayName="user82" LastEditDate="2011-12-23T22:21:09.773" LastActivityDate="2011-12-23T22:21:09.773" CommentCount="3" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="4721" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2012-01-09T17:56:49.890" Score="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;One position I find comfortable is to put my backpack on the tray table, put a pillow or blanket on it, and sleep slouched forward on my backpack-pillow. It's often more stable than &quot;reclining&quot; back as much as I can and hoping my head doesn't roll around. It's also a bit closer to horizontal, and puts that much less vertical pressure on your spine. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, you become an impassable obstacle, so I only do it when I'm in the window seat, or when the people I'm blocking know me, and won't feel weird about waking me up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="395" LastActivityDate="2012-01-09T17:56:49.890" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="10999" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2012-12-04T22:03:37.897" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Use earplugs to reduce the noise.  I recommend the silicone putty type ones since you can mold them to the shape of your ear opening.  The foam ones aren't that great since you have to shove them all the way into your eardrums.  The flange-shaped ones can be uncomfortable as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="3686" LastEditorUserId="101" LastEditDate="2012-12-04T22:12:18.850" LastActivityDate="2012-12-04T22:12:18.850" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="16539" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2013-04-15T18:28:42.567" Score="34" Body="&lt;p&gt;While there is plenty of good advice in the other answers, I feel I have some more to offer that is a little less spontaneous. Sleeping on a plane is a &lt;strong&gt;learned skill&lt;/strong&gt; and it is improved by planning, preparation, and practice. You can change the likelihood of sleep from nearly nil to nearly guaranteed, but not if the first time you start to think about it is as the plane starts to taxi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, the booking. Generally you have some choice here. Should you leave early in the morning, or late at night? At 4pm, ensuring you'll be hungry after a few hours in the air, or at 8pm, when you're more likely to show up having eaten enough to last you through the night? If it's a 7 hour flight and you need to stay awake for 2 hours to get food, you're not getting more than 5 hours of sleep. Pick a flight that either won't require you to sleep much, or that lets you organize the rest of your day to maximize the time you have for sleeping. Also think about whether a glass of wine would help - it's much easier to get one (bought in the airport, say) at 7pm than at 7am. Here is also where you settle window/aisle (I like window because it gives me a wall to lean on and a few more inches of space from my seat to the wall), consider paying for more legroom in a premium seat for $100 or so more, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second, the packing. NEVER count on the airline for pillows, blankets etc. Sometimes they don't get them. Sometimes they can't give you one until the seatbelt sign is off. Airline pillows are small and weird and most annoyingly, they're slippery and they fall between your seat and the wall. Bring your own. A bed pillow from home, one of those C-shaped things (solid or inflatable), something. I like an inflatable one with a VERY fuzzy cover and a little pocket for eyeshades:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/kGLdD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;inflatable pillow&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don't decline blankets or pillows from the airplane though - they are handy for padding the armrest so I can lean against it or over it without the edge digging into me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continuing with packing, I bring my own blanket in the form of a pashmina which folds very small but unfolds enough to cover all of me (6' x 2' I suppose.) I generally use separate blankets for my top and bottom half, to help the crew see that my seatbelt is fastened and to let me move more freely. If the airline doesn't give out blankets I'll use a coat on my legs. My pillow and blanket are familiar and comfortable, they smell right, and I never worry if they're clean. The eyeshade makes a huge difference also, both in keeping out the light and in telling people you are sleeping and don't want a drink, a newspaper, dinner, duty free, etc. And for me, the sensation of the eyeshade on my face reminds me I am supposed to be sleeping. Noise cancelling headphones and a playlist of relaxing and enjoyable music are also on the packing list. These are better than earlugs in my experience, though I always have a few earplugs in the bag just in case. Over-the-ear can be uncomfortable to lie on, so I use earbuds. Plug into the entertainment system when you board, put them in, go to sleep. If you wake later, switch to your playlist and put your seat back. When you have to put your seat up, switch back to their system. I also choose shoes I can slip off and slip back on rather than ones that need tying. Your laceups can be in your checked luggage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So you chose the right flight and seat, you packed the right stuff and you're at the airport. Eat, drink, go to the bathroom. These are all good ways to pass the time while you're waiting to board. Also bring an empty water bottle with you that you can fill after security, or buy water in the airport. That way if you wake up thirsty you can immediately fix that and go back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now on the plane, all you need to do is sleep. Don't put the pillow around your neck. You have so little recline, you don't need to prop your head up. Put it between the side of your head and the wall. Put your ear in the centre hole so it doesn't get squished. Coat over legs, blanket over shoulder and chest. Snuggled up warm and cosy, listening to something you like, with a water bottle in easy reach and a clear &quot;leave me alone&quot; sign on your eyes, you will sleep. You just will. And trust me, it is so much better than a book or that movie you never got around to watching in theatres. You will get better at it every time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you wake up, especially if you're uncomfortable, change your position. Loosen your seatbelt as much as you can and sort of turn on your side. Or move your feet from on top of the carryon you stuffed under the seat in front of you, to next to it. Adjust your blankets a little. Move your pillow more under your chin. Your approach should be that you will do what you need to do to go back to sleep, not &quot;oh well I tried but I woke up.&quot; Don't worry about what time it is. You won't miss your stop. If you wake up again, then try a third position. You'll find something comfortable eventually. If you feel anxious when you wake up, especially if you're getting caught up in the &quot;oh noes now I will only get three hours sleep, I am ruining my trip&quot; then try switching from your playlist to some guided relaxations and meditations. Many airlines have them in the inflight system, or you can bring your own. It's as good as sleeping in terms of refreshing your brain and body, and could (usually does) lead to falling asleep too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn from each flight and adjust what you bring and do. You will become one of those people who finds it &quot;effortless&quot; and easy to sleep on planes. It's not that easy and then again, it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="46" LastEditorUserId="46" LastEditDate="2013-04-22T19:14:44.360" LastActivityDate="2013-04-22T19:14:44.360" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="16966" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2013-04-30T04:14:39.077" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been known to convert an airplane blanket into a neck pillow. Supporting your neck can save a lot of pain later in the day. This quick tip (when the plane is cool enough) has helped me several times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roll up the blanket, long way like a salami.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fold in half.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Place around neck like a scarf, tucking the loose end through the bend in the blanket.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pull it very tight and tuck the loose end behind you. Don't worry, it will loosen up a little, and you need some tension to keep the function.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the trouble sleeping on planes, it takes practice, but I find sleeping on a plane to be easier than other public locations. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6537" LastActivityDate="2013-04-30T04:14:39.077" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="19518" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2013-08-07T15:21:12.100" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of good answers here, but since my approach is different, I'll share it as well.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Usually the time my flights is rather short (1-2 hours), and therefore also in less comfortable planes. Most people seem to accept the rather small space you have on e.g. a Ryanair flight, I actually appreciate it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;I lean forward, lean my head on the seat in front, facing forward, and close my eyes.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure hair or cloth/napkin is between you and the seat, to avoid logos embossed on your face and beware of drooling.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Chew bubble gum, it will make sure pain in the ears won't wake you while taking off and it keeps you from opening your mouth. Sure, you're not really chewing, but it still helps with the ears. Start relaxing as soon as you are seated, taking off can actually help falling asleep.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For me this works like a charm. I was unable to nap on planes as well, now I can't stay awake. Once I even fell asleep on the way to an interview.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The benefits are&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No neck pain (if the seats are close enough together)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No addition to the already limited hand luggage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Works on all seats, so on airlines without booked seating you don't have to stand in line the entire time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As soon as you manage once, you'll see airplanes as rather large cradles, so good luck.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4849" LastActivityDate="2013-08-07T15:21:12.100" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="19518" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2013-08-07T15:21:12.100" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of good answers here, but since my approach is different, I'll share it as well.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Usually the time my flights is rather short (1-2 hours), and therefore also in less comfortable planes. Most people seem to accept the rather small space you have on e.g. a Ryanair flight, I actually appreciate it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;I lean forward, lean my head on the seat in front, facing forward, and close my eyes.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure hair or cloth/napkin is between you and the seat, to avoid logos embossed on your face and beware of drooling.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Chew bubble gum, it will make sure pain in the ears won't wake you while taking off and it keeps you from opening your mouth. Sure, you're not really chewing, but it still helps with the ears. Start relaxing as soon as you are seated, taking off can actually help falling asleep.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For me this works like a charm. I was unable to nap on planes as well, now I can't stay awake. Once I even fell asleep on the way to an interview.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The benefits are&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No neck pain (if the seats are close enough together)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No addition to the already limited hand luggage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Works on all seats, so on airlines without booked seating you don't have to stand in line the entire time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As soon as you manage once, you'll see airplanes as rather large cradles, so good luck.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4849" LastActivityDate="2013-08-07T15:21:12.100" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="19530" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2013-08-08T00:39:32.867" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;I know it's not what the OP asked for, but as one of those people like Mark Mayo who has extreme difficulty sleeping while sitting up (and who's never gotten much better at it despite 700K miles of &quot;practice&quot;), the solution to sleeping on planes is &lt;strong&gt;flying business class&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And before you gasp and say &quot;But that's stupidly expensive!&quot;, there are ways to fly in the pointy end of the plane without breaking the bank.  &lt;em&gt;Frequent flyer miles&lt;/em&gt; is the big one, for me there's no better way to use my miles than to book or upgrade to business class on overnight long-haul flights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you're paying and need to get from A to B but are not in a huge hurry, don't even bother looking a business class on the direct flights (it'll cost 4-7x more than economy), instead look for &lt;em&gt;weird routings&lt;/em&gt;: A to Z to B.  For example, I once needed to get from Singapore to LA and back: the direct business class fare was north of S$9000 on Singapore Airlines, with economy fares hovering around S$2000 mark, but I managed to find a biz fare on Asiana via Seoul for under S$3000.  This involved a 16-hour layover in Seoul on the way, but as a business class passenger Asiana threw in a free hotel room and a free lunch, plus I got to stretch my legs a bit in Seoul.  Win!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you're splurging on a &lt;em&gt;round-the-world trip&lt;/em&gt;, consider splurging a bit more and getting a business class fare.  Yes, it'll cost you around twice the economy price (although &lt;a href=&quot;https://travel.stackexchange.com/questions/5914/should-i-buy-an-around-the-world-ticket-from-australia-or-a-nearby-country&quot;&gt;there's ways to cut that as well&lt;/a&gt;), but you'll get to do all your long-hauls in style plus get access to lounges, priority check-in, priority immigration, etc for the entirety of your trip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1893" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:52:10.040" LastActivityDate="2013-08-08T00:39:32.867" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="21589" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4308" CreationDate="2013-11-03T00:25:16.783" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;While travelling the best way I do is Listen to Musical Meditations it helps a lot give relaxation to mind and body. I will suggest have some soft Music collection with you will help  a lot to make you avoid noise and sleep well...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8732" LastActivityDate="2013-11-03T00:25:16.783" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

---

<row Id="4722" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4720" CreationDate="2012-01-09T18:35:02.143" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've not slept in this airport, so I can't give you personal information. Nevertheless there is a site called &quot;Sleep in Airports&quot; that gives general information about sleeping in almost any airport. About Chicago O'Hare, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sleepinginairports.net/usa/chicago_ohare.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; says that you can sleep in a lounge for US$40-50, there are 3 hotels and if you are looking for a free nap you have some reviews about where and how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1425" LastEditorUserId="101" LastEditDate="2012-01-10T22:59:52.437" LastActivityDate="2012-01-10T22:59:52.437" CommentCount="3" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="9527" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4720" CreationDate="2012-09-14T19:03:41.173" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;I use those Admirals' Clubs regularly. They are OK. The food and drinks options are poor, but the showers are pretty nice. There are also some comfortable chairs which recline, which might be good for sleeping, although they can go quickly. The quiet rooms generally &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; quiet, but they don't contain the reclining chairs (from memory).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aa.com/i18n/travelInformation/airportAmenities/admiralsClubArticles/oneDayPass.jsp&amp;amp;locale=es_ES&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;It costs $50 for a day pass&lt;/a&gt;, so you can decide if that's worth it to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you are in Terminal 3, it's also worth checking out the Virgin America gates along concourse L, which have powerports, and the new Mexican place near Gate K8 or so (best food in the terminal).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="2555" LastEditorUserId="2555" LastEditDate="2012-12-17T09:53:43.763" LastActivityDate="2012-12-17T09:53:43.763" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="9384" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1014" CreationDate="2012-09-07T15:34:43.667" Score="16" Body="&lt;p&gt;For the scientifically minded, this is well documented in medical research. Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2829880/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for a lot of info. Their recommended procedure is shown in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2829880/figure/F4/&quot;&gt;this figure&lt;/a&gt;. The basic points: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No miracle cure: your body adjusts slowly, and aggressive tactics to shift by more than an hour or so a day won't help. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunlight exposure is key: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you're traveling west, avoid early morning sun starting a few days before your trip. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you're traveling east, be sure to get early morning sun. Again, starting a day or so before the trip helps. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you can't get sunlight, a full-spectrum &quot;lightbox&quot; is the next best thing. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Melatonin also helps when traveling east, but should be taken 4.5 hours before sleep. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="2342" LastEditorUserId="2342" LastEditDate="2013-03-26T21:17:24.340" LastActivityDate="2013-03-26T21:17:24.340" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="13500" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="13494" CreationDate="2013-02-12T14:45:13.260" Score="17" Body="&lt;p&gt;I strongly prefer window seats, but once found myself in an aisle seat for a TransAtlantic flight. As I sat down, the man in the middle seat said &quot;excuse me, but my son [gesturing to the window seat] is extremely claustrophobic. Is there any way you could change seats with him just for takeoff?&quot; I couldn't believe my luck. I WANTED that window seat! &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We changed places for the duration, and during the times when you aren't allowed to get up,  he could at least lean out into the aisle and not have a seatback right in front of his face. He also got up and paced a lot. At the end of the flight, they thanked me again (which was crazy, so I thanked them) and apparently it had been a pretty unpleasant 8 hours, but he had got through it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So do try to get an aisle seat. It made a big difference for him. If you end up in something else, ask those around you if you can trade and explain why. (I understand some people prefer aisle to window and might not trade, but you might luck out and meet me, or someone generous enough to trade even though they prefer the aisle.) Ask the flight crew if they can find you an aisle seat or arrange a trade with someone further away. And try to choose a flight at a time when you can sleep - nobody actually enjoys sitting on airplanes so if you can be asleep for some of it, so much the better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="46" LastEditorUserId="46" LastEditDate="2013-02-12T17:58:37.090" LastActivityDate="2013-02-12T17:58:37.090" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="13503" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="13494" CreationDate="2013-02-12T17:11:03.770" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;First of all, long flights are Claustrophobia friendly :) most likely they will be operated using big airplanes (B777, A330, B747 ..etc). These airplanes are huge with high ceilings and wide bodies, these features will surely ease the feeling of restriction. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, being a cabin crew with a highly claustrophobic mother who couldn't even have an MRI without being drugged I have few tips (some already mentioned in other answers) that for sure will help you through this experience as it did to my mother who now flies with no problems at all:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go for the aisle seat. Whenever you feel restricted just stand up and move! avoid the middle seats! these middle seats will even make people with no claustrophobia feel uncomfortable and restricted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try to find an empty row or a seat next to an empty seat, having empty space around you will ease the feeling of restriction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You must know that the suffocation feeling people with claustrophobia get is due to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperventilation&quot;&gt;Hyperventilation&lt;/a&gt; and not a real suffocation. So if you ever feel suffocated just breath into the airsickness bag in the seat pocket in front of you, this will let the suffocation feeling go away instantly. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you ever feel the claustrophobia symptoms (restriction and suffocation) and you can not do anything about it, talk to the cabin crew. They are trained to deal with this kind of things and they will try their best to make you feel better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get busy with the in-flight entertaining system or your own iPad or so. Claustrophobia comes from negative thoughts, so fight it by keeping your head busy!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Over the counter sleeping pills may help you sleep during the flight. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talking to people helps a lot in all kinds of anxiety. We usually tell passengers around to talk to the person with anxiety, aviophobia or claustrophobia. Talking will keep your mind busy and stop it from starting the negative thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am sure if you were able to do your shorter flight which most probably was on smaller airplane then you will do this flight with no problems. Just remember no one actually dies from claustrophobia! and remember these two long flights are a good treatment for claustrophobia, it was proven that exposure has reduced the negative thoughts by 75% in people with claustrophobia (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claustrophobia#In_vivo_exposure&quot;&gt;In vivo exposure&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10051" OwnerDisplayName="user1712" LastEditorUserId="10051" LastActivityDate="2013-02-12T17:11:03.770" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="18137" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1014" CreationDate="2013-06-15T22:45:30.273" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;One point that hasn't been mentioned: Watch out for &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you eat or drink.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently traveled to Switzerland, thus getting up 7 hours earlier, and did what I usually do: Little or no sleep on the way over, and immediately adjust to the local time.  But I had a terrible time getting over jet lag.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be due to cereal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some reason, dairy products make me sleepy (milk, ice cream, etc.).  At my hotel, I had a bowl or two of cereal for breakfast in the morning.  I'd return to my room and practically crash.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So before you go, make a plan about what and when you'll eat and drink.  In my case, it would be:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Morning&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;no cereal with milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;soda with caffeine is OK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evening&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cereal with milk is OK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;no soda with caffeine after 5 pm&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You'll have to make your personal list based on what you might eat or drink that makes you sleepy (e.g. alcohol) or wakeful (chocolate, which has caffeine, or coffee).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="2618" LastActivityDate="2013-06-15T22:45:30.273" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="36347" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1014" CreationDate="2014-09-10T17:06:17.020" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://harpers.org/blog/2012/03/the-empty-stomach-fasting-to-beat-jet-lag/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; describes what is known as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netlib.org/misc/jet-lag-diet&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Argonne Anti-Jet-Lag-Diet&lt;/a&gt; and is a method which seems deceptively simple, while contradicting some bits of advice offered by other answers here.  I have yet to try it myself, but a coworker says it works wonders for his wife on trans-Atlantic trips, and for his brother on cross-continental-US trips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The basic concept is to fool your body's internal clock by changing your eating habits. The basic plan works like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DETERMINE BREAKFAST TIME at destination on day of arrival.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;FEAST-FAST-FEAST-FAST - Start four days before breakfast time in step 1. On day one, FEAST; eat heartily with high-protein breakfast and lunch and a high-carbohydrate dinner. No coffee except between 3 and 5 p.m. On day two, FAST on light meals of salads, light soups, fruits and juices. Again, no coffee except between 3 and 5 p.m. On day three, FEAST again. On day four, FAST; if you drink caffeinated beverages, take them in morning when traveling west, or between 6 and 11 p.m. when traveling east.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BREAK THE FINAL FAST at destination breakfast time. No alcohol on the plane. If the flight is long enough, sleep until normal breakfast time at destination, but no later. Wake up and FEAST on a high protein breakfast. Stay awake and active. Continue the day's meals according to mealtimes at the destination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="444" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2020-06-16T10:18:57.393" LastActivityDate="2014-09-10T17:06:17.020" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="106850" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1014" CreationDate="2017-12-16T14:09:20.533" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;What really helped me, flying east w/ 8 hour time difference:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sleep earlier and earlier&lt;/strong&gt; on days leading up to the flight. I change my waking time from 8am to 4am gradually. This translates to waking at midday in the destination timezone. Important because you can only adjust by 1 hour a day!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the day of the flight I wake up at 4am, drink no caffeine and take an overnight flight. I usually don't sleep much, but that's fine. Due to the timezone adjustment, the day after the flight is only half as long as normal, combined with being tired, means you're likely to sleep at a sensible time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The flight sleep debt can be paid back over any number of days and you only need to make up for 1/3 of your lost hours, so it doesn't affect much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the flight back I try to avoid an overnight flight, because due to timezone differences the day will be super long (8 hours longer than normal) and going ~46 hours without sleep is a recipe for disaster. I take a day flight, stay awake until I reach my destination, then crash. Staying awake is much easier than sleeping earlier for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="71548" LastActivityDate="2017-12-16T14:09:20.533" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="18483" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18192" CreationDate="2013-06-28T07:48:51.793" Score="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;Taking sleeper trains in China is an interesting experience and one you will remember for a long time. Whither you enjoy it or not depends on the frame of mine you have. In my opinion it beats the bus on all levels and ties with flying only because flying is generally faster. Sleaper trains have the advantage of saving you a nights hotel bill and usually take you from city centre to city centre so you don't need taxis and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It can sometimes be a bit of an adventure. Few people will speak English. Trains in China don't operate in the same manor as European trains. It is a bit more like an airport style operation where you wait in the waiting room for the train to be called, then everyone piles through the gates in just a few minutes and charge down to the platform. However, the train's staff are usually very diligent in their jobs. If you treat them politely they will look after you well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have taken about a dozen hard sleepers and one soft sleeper. Personally I think the hard sleeper is better. You see more of the people and can interact with other passengers better. There is more space between the bunks for storing luggage. There are fold down seats in the isle for people to sit on where as soft sleepers everyone just sits on the bottom bunk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That brings me to the choice of bunks. When you buy your tickets, you can request a top or middle or bottom bunk. Be aware that the top bunk is more cramped. The bottom bunk will be used by the people above for sitting when your not sleeping. So the middle bunk is best.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You mention that you are travelling as a group of three so I would suggest you try to get two middle bunks and a bottom bunk. The three of you can sit on the bottom bunk together but still stay together when sleeping. If you get three middle bunks, then one of you will be in a separate bay on their own at night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bathroom facilities on the train tend to be very basic (hole in floor for WC). So shower before leaving your hotel and be prepared to wear the same underwear all night and into the next day. Take some light weight pants and T-shirts to wear at night. When you get off the train, go straight to your hotel, check in, shower and change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, bring some food with you. On train food choices are quite limited. The Chinese usually by or bring quick noodles and cook them using the hot water supplied on the train. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="602" LastActivityDate="2013-06-28T07:48:51.793" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

---

<row Id="581" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="86" CreationDate="2011-06-29T00:20:05.713" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;For Ha Long bay from Hanoi you can just get yourself a bus ticket from the bus station. If you are considering Ha Long Bay also consider Cat Ba Island. I have heard mixed reports of Ha Long Bay tours. I was warned a really cheap tour is generally a really bad tour but I rock climbed with a guy on Cat Ba Island who took a cheap tour and said it was great. I think the quality of the sleeping on the boat was generaly the issue.&#xA;I travelled by bus to Cat Ba with Hoang Long Bus Company. I think they go to Ha Long city as well. &#xA;If you buy a Ha Long Bay tour though, it may include transport from Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="208" LastActivityDate="2011-06-29T00:20:05.713" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="1161" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1146" CreationDate="2011-07-21T16:06:34.230" Score="12" Body="&lt;p&gt;Buses are great - in Argentina, they're comfortable, serve food, and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pick one going overnight, sleep on the bus (get full-cama, not semi-cama - your seat will become a bed!) and be there in the next day!&#xA;Head to Retiro bus station in Buenos Aires, they all go from there, go upstairs to the 2nd floor and to the area for north-bound buses.  There will be plenty available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recommend Che Legarto hostel in Puerto Iguazu, very convenient and they speak great English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="101" LastActivityDate="2011-07-21T16:06:34.230" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="18664" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18663" CreationDate="2013-07-07T12:02:34.927" Score="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;If you're travelling on a budget - which I assume you are because you're staying in hostels - then the key thing would be to find a place to spend the night in Macau. The only hostel that I know of in Macau was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.augusters.de/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Augusters Lodge&lt;/a&gt; (they weren't on Hostelworld) but as far as I know they shut down. So the only option for &quot;cheap&quot; accommodation that's left is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.couchsurfing.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other option for exploring the nightlife of Macau is to crash and catch some sleep in a casino. The big ones like City of Dreams or the Venetian don't really care. The ferry from Hong Kong to Macau doesn't take too long though, so if you feel tired then you can easily head back to your Hong Kong hostel to get sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="108" LastActivityDate="2013-07-07T12:02:34.927" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="18671" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18670" CreationDate="2013-07-07T22:28:21.780" Score="12" Body="&lt;p&gt;Firstly, be aware that there are three possible lavatory placings - at the front, midway in the plane, and at the back.  The lavatory row at the back is 'special' as it's something people don't always realise - this row usually doesn't have reclining seats.  Well worth noting.  I regularly choose the back of the plane to get away from the kid-aisle with the bassinets further forward, but each flight has its own areas with their own merits.  As a result of where I tend to choose, I am often near a bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it sounds like you're asking more about the mid-way lavatories, so I'll just describe lavatory seats in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I have anosmia (no sense of smell), so that side of things isn't a problem. Obviously the stronger your sense of smell, the worse it's going to get if there are issues with the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, there's the inevitable queue.  Although most planes have those handy signs to tell you when the toilet is in use, people still like to get up and queue - either because it's urgent for them, or even just to stand for a while and stretch those legs. What this means as a person close to the bathroom is that you constantly have people standing next to you, bumping you accidentally, watching your tv, chatting to each other right next to you, or potentially (horror!) even trying to make smalltalk with you!  If you're trying to sleep, this can be very frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nwxt there's the noise from the bathroom itself. You'll rarely hear actual ... 'functions' inside, but you will hear the flush, and some people have a tendency to slam the door open and make a racket.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It's also worth noting, as I alluded to before earlier, that midway bathrooms can sometimes be near the aisle with the bassinets and babies.  This can be noisy and distracting as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, long story short - if, like me, you don't even try to sleep on planes and have no sense of smell, I prefer the back of the plane (but not the very back row) and the aisle seat so that I can get up and wander a bit.  If you like to sleep on a plane, don't watch movies, and have a stronger sense of smell, you may find it a very problematic and frustrating flight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="101" LastActivityDate="2013-07-07T22:28:21.780" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="18969" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18968" CreationDate="2013-07-18T12:56:16.707" Score="17" Body="&lt;p&gt;On long haul flights there are often seats reserved for crew rest. One crew works 5 hours or so then changes clothes and goes to those seats to eat, read, gossip and possibly sleep. The other crew, who was in those seats, changes and takes over duties. They use the very back row because it's close to where working crew hang out during the flight anyway. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've seen this happen on SAA, complete with changing into uniform-like clothing that is more like sweatpants than a typical flight attendant outfit, on an 18 hour flight (with a tech stop.) I've also seen them unpack their own food to eat at that time - the catering on the flight is I guess not for them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don't think it's actually every flight, but it could be that for BA, all widebody flights are long haul. Pilots can typically rest in the cockpit, or on some planes there is an upstairs cubby where pilots can rest between shifts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="46" LastActivityDate="2013-07-18T12:56:16.707" CommentCount="5" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="27502" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="9885" CreationDate="2014-05-23T01:41:30.953" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Drinking a lot of alcohol before or during a flight is not a healthy option.  It interferes with sleep and exacerbates jet lag.  Anti-anxiety medication might be a good idea (check with your doctor), and there are clinically accepted non-drug anti-anxiety techniques that a psychologist can teach you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="13848" LastActivityDate="2014-05-23T01:41:30.953" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<row Id="18998" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18995" CreationDate="2013-07-19T15:32:41.243" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;If you travel far enough poleward during summer, you reach the land of the Midnight Sun.  That certainly messes up sleep for many people.  Although days are not exactly short in the UK or Germany in June or July, it not getting dark at all is a different story algother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I live in the far north and spent a month in the USA in May.  I didn't suffer from jetlag much when I travelled westward, but when I travelled eastward again early June, the complete lack of a night (the Sun set again 3 days ago for the first time since May) was certainly a complicating factor, considering that this was the view from my bedroom at 0:15 the night after I got back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/1CD4S.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bedroom view 0:15&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="2509" LastActivityDate="2013-07-19T15:32:41.243" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />

<--trap q-->

<row Id="36671" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="29141" CreationDate="2014-09-20T20:58:47.830" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;From my experience, the biggest thing to prevent jet lag is to set your watch to your destination's local time at the gate while you are waiting to board.  Mentally commit to the new &quot;local&quot; time and do everything you can to get a jump start on acclimating your body (ie sleeping or staying awake when you need to). This includes skipping meal services if need be. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In your specific example you would be boarding at 6pm Korea time which is 5am EST, so I would recommend staying awake during the entire flight, or at least sleeping as little as possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I typically like to stay away from soda or coffee that has caffeine, as this alters your body's natural sleep cycle. However, in your case it may be useful to help stay awake during the flight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some other things that work best for me are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eat Light, heavy foods suck my energy &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stay hydrated, water or a sports drink&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid caffeine, (unless deliberately trying to stay&#xA;awake)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="20273" LastEditorUserId="27650" LastEditDate="2016-10-29T20:59:26.977" LastActivityDate="2016-10-29T20:59:26.977" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
